{
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "What is a state in React?",
      "options": [
        "External storage of the component",
        "A permanent storage",
        "Internal storage of the component",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Internal storage of the component"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Does React.js create a VIRTUAL DOM in the memory?",
      "options": ["True", "False", "Cannot say", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Which of the following is used to pass data to a component from outside in React.js?",
      "options": ["Render with arguments", "PropTypes", "SetState", "Props"],
      "answer": "Props"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "What are the two ways to handle data in React?",
      "options": [
        "Services & Components",
        "State & Component",
        "State & Props",
        "State & Services"
      ],
      "answer": "State & Props"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Which of the following is the correct name of React.js?",
      "options": ["React.js", "React", "ReactJS", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "What does ES6 stand for?",
      "options": [
        "ECMAJavaScript 6",
        "ECMA 6",
        "ECMAScript 6",
        "EJavaScript 6"
      ],
      "answer": "ECMAScript 6"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "What is the use of “web pack” command in React.js?",
      "options": [
        "It is a module bundler",
        "The “webpack” command is used to transpile all the JavaScript down into one file",
        "It runs React local development server",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "It is a module bundler"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "In which of the following directory React.js components are saved?",
      "options": [
        "Inside the vendor/components/",
        "Inside the vendor/",
        "Inside the js/components/",
        "Inside the external/components/"
      ],
      "answer": "Inside the js/components/"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "Which of the following function is used to change the state of the React.js component?",
      "options": [
        "this.setChangeState",
        "this.State{}",
        "this.setState",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "this.setState"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "In which of the following condition, the React.js Lifecycle method static get Derived Stae From Props(props, state) is called?",
      "options": [
        "The state of the component is updated",
        "The component is created for the first time",
        "All of above",
        "None"
      ],
      "answer": "All of above"
    }
  ]
}
